<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Android on Stephen&#39;s Tech Blog</title>
    <link>https://stephenn.com/tags/android/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Android on Stephen&#39;s Tech Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 18:49:00 -0800</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://stephenn.com/tags/android/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>TM Watcher Android app</title>
      <link>https://stephenn.com/2010/11/tm-watcher-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Nov 2010 18:49:00 -0800</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephenn.com/2010/11/tm-watcher-android-app/</guid>
      <description>TM Watcher for Trademe.co.nzTM Watcher checks auctions in your Trademe watchlist to see when any of their attributes change, then notify the user. This includes attributes like bid price, end date.--I&#39;ve put alot more polish into this than ODW, it feels good. I figured out how to have it run something at boot, which has the effect of greatly simplifying the user controls improving the user experience, compared to that of ODW.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>One Day Watcher Android app</title>
      <link>https://stephenn.com/2010/10/one-day-watcher-android-app/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 08 Oct 2010 02:49:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephenn.com/2010/10/one-day-watcher-android-app/</guid>
      <description>I finished/published version 1.0 of my first android app today. One Day Watcher.This app automatically checks 1-day.co.nz for you, so you dont have to. It checks for keywords that you set, and gives you notification with the results.Check it out at http://code.google.com/p/one-day-watcher/or search for it on the Android Market.It&#39;ll be interesting to see if many people find it useful.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>How to restore your nexus one with the original shipping roms then
update to 2.2.1</title>
      <link>https://stephenn.com/2010/09/how-to-restore-your-nexus-one-with/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Sep 2010 01:32:00 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://stephenn.com/2010/09/how-to-restore-your-nexus-one-with/</guid>
      <description>This will remove everything off your device, except stuff on the sd-card. I take no responsibility if you somehow brick the it ;). You will end up running 2.2.1 unrooted.
This was written for the at&amp;t nexus one. Im not sure if there are any differences for the other one. You should be able to give this a go, and if the radio doesnt work with this stuff, you can always find the right stuff and re flash it.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
